<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <atom:link href="https://rss.hiiraan.com/rss.xml" rel="self" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"/>
  <title>
   Hiiraan Online
  </title>
  <link>
   http://www.hiiraan.com
  </link>
  <description>
   Welcome to Hiiraan Online, your source of news and information about Somalia
  </description>
  <language>
   en-us
  </language>
  <copyright>
   ï¿½ 2018 hiiraan.com
  </copyright>
  <pubDate>
   Thu, 5 Jun 2025 12:04 EDT
  </pubDate>
  <ttl>
   5
  </ttl>
  <image>
   <title>
    Hiiraan Online
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com
   </link>
   <url>
    http://www.hiiraan.com//holimages3/hiiraan-online.png
   </url>
   <width>
    144
   </width>
   <height>
    99
   </height>
   <description>
    Welcome to Hiiraan Online, your source of news and information about Somalia
   </description>
  </image>
  <item>
   <title>
    Farmaajo criticizes upcoming National Consultation Forum, warns of deepening political crisis
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201763/former_president_farmaajo_criticizes_upcoming_national_consultation_forum_warns_of_deepening_political_crisis.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Former Somali President Mohamed Abdullahi Farmaajo has issued a strong statement criticizing the management and inclusivity of the upcoming National Consultation Forum called by President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 12:04 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201763/former_president_farmaajo_criticizes_upcoming_national_consultation_forum_warns_of_deepening_political_crisis.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali police arrest suspected Al-Shabaab bombmakers after Mogadishu house explosion
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201762/somali_police_arrest_suspected_al_shabaab_bombmakers_after_mogadishu_house_explosion.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somali police arrested several suspected Al-Shabaab members on Thursday after an explosion at a house in Mogadishu’s Dayniile district revealed an apparent bomb-making operation.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 07:00 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201762/somali_police_arrest_suspected_al_shabaab_bombmakers_after_mogadishu_house_explosion.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somaliland is open to trade, innovation and dialogue
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201761/somaliland_is_open_to_trade_innovation_and_dialogue.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    The warm welcome I received in Nairobi this past week is a testament to the enduring spirit of African solidarity and the potential of regional partnership.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 06:29 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201761/somaliland_is_open_to_trade_innovation_and_dialogue.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Premier Bank Revolutionizes Cross-Border Payments with Direct SWIFT Service
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201760/premier_bank_revolutionizes_cross_border_payments_with_direct_swift_service.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu, June 3, 2025 – Premier Bank is proud to announce the launch of its enhanced direct SWIFT payment platform, transforming international money transfers by enabling businesses and individuals in the country to send and receive funds globally — faster, simpler, and more secure than ever before.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 06:12 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201760/premier_bank_revolutionizes_cross_border_payments_with_direct_swift_service.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Nearly two million pilgrims ascend mount Arafat for peak of Hajj pilgrimage
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201759/nearly_two_million_pilgrims_ascend_mount_arafat_for_peak_of_hajj_pilgrimage.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) - Nearly two million Muslim pilgrims gathered on Mount Arafat in western Saudi Arabia on Thursday, marking the spiritual climax of the annual Hajj pilgrimage.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 05:52 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201759/nearly_two_million_pilgrims_ascend_mount_arafat_for_peak_of_hajj_pilgrimage.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia’s Electoral Commission denies reports of forced voter registration in Mogadishu
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201758/somalia_s_electoral_commission_denies_reports_of_forced_voter_registration_in_mogadishu.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Somalia’s Independent National Electoral Commission has strongly denied recent allegations circulating on social media that residents in Mogadishu are being forced to collect their voting cards under threat of arrest.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:29 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201758/somalia_s_electoral_commission_denies_reports_of_forced_voter_registration_in_mogadishu.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Ma’awisley militia kills 20 Al-Shabaab fighters in fierce clashes in Hiiraan region
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201757/ma_awisley_militia_kills_20_al_shabaab_fighters_in_fierce_clashes_in_hiiraan_region.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Beledweyne (HOL) – At least 20 Al-Shabaab militants were killed on Wednesday during heavy fighting between Ma’awisley local militia forces from the Hawadle clan and the militant group in the El-Hareri area of the Hiiraan region.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:18 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201757/ma_awisley_militia_kills_20_al_shabaab_fighters_in_fierce_clashes_in_hiiraan_region.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Factory jobs in Harfo provide opportunity for Mudug families
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201756/factory_jobs_in_harfo_provide_opportunity_for_mudug_families.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Getting a job in a new factory in Harfo, in central Somalia’s Mudug region, has meant that Ahmed Abdikhayr Jama can provide fully for his family of eight and has dropped the idea of migrating overseas in search of work.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:05 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201756/factory_jobs_in_harfo_provide_opportunity_for_mudug_families.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia rolls out key reforms in immigration agency
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201755/somalia_rolls_out_key_reforms_in_immigration_agency.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Somalia’s Immigration and Citizenship Agency (ICA) has announced a raft of sweeping reforms and milestones achieved in its mid-year performance report, signaling a transformative leap in how the country manages migration, border control, and public services.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:01 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201755/somalia_rolls_out_key_reforms_in_immigration_agency.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Trump reinstates US travel ban, bars citizens of 12 countries
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201754/trump_reinstates_us_travel_ban_bars_citizens_of_12_countries.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    U.S. President Donald Trump signed a proclamation on Wednesday banning the citizens of 12 countries from entering the United States, saying the move was needed to protect against "foreign terrorists" and other security threats.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 02:59 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201754/trump_reinstates_us_travel_ban_bars_citizens_of_12_countries.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Kenyan muslims raise Ksh.5.4M for Gaza relief in Eid-ul-Adha initiative
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201753/kenyan_muslims_raise_ksh_5_4m_for_gaza_relief_in_eid_ul_adha_initiative.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Kenya’s Muslim community has raised Ksh.5.4 million to feed starving Gazans during Eid-ul-Adha through the Gaza-Udhiya Program 2025.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 02:54 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201753/kenyan_muslims_raise_ksh_5_4m_for_gaza_relief_in_eid_ul_adha_initiative.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Portugal turns the tables on Germany in Nations League semifinal
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201752/portugal_turns_the_tables_on_germany_in_nations_league_semifinal.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Cristiano Ronaldo scored the decisive goal as Portugal came from behind to defeat Germany 2-1 in the UEFA Nations League semifinal in Munich on Wednesday, ending the hosts' hopes of reaching the tournament final for the first time.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Thu, 5 Jun 2025 02:48 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201752/portugal_turns_the_tables_on_germany_in_nations_league_semifinal.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Modernizing Somalia’s Consumer Price Index
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201751/modernizing_somalia_s_consumer_price_index.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    On May 4, 2025, the Somalia National Bureau of Statistics (SNBS) achieved a historic milestone by launching a modernized Consumer Price Index (CPI). This was the first nationally representative CPI. A few weeks later, on May 22nd, the Bureau released the first quarterly CPI report under this new framework. The report provided rich information and analysis about price dynamics across the country. This achievement represents an imperative shift from a CPI that focused only on Mogadishu (Banadir region) to a comprehensive national and state-level price monitoring system. Puntland and Somaliland previously conducted CPI separately, though with outdated methodologies. The move towards integrated national CPI will lead to enhanced data quality, transparency, and relevance in national planning and policymaking.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 13:50 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201751/modernizing_somalia_s_consumer_price_index.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    President Mohamud meets political party leaders ahead of June National Consultation Forum
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201750/president_mohamud_meets_political_party_leaders_ahead_of_june_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Somali President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud convened a high-level meeting on Wednesday with leaders of registered political parties at the Presidential Palace in Mogadishu as part of preparations for the National Consultation Forum scheduled for June 15, 2025.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 07:18 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201750/president_mohamud_meets_political_party_leaders_ahead_of_june_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Puntland's Dervish Forces kill over 35 ISIS fighters in Bari region offensive
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201749/puntland_s_dervish_forces_kill_over_35_isis_fighters_in_bari_region_offensive.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Bosaso (HOL) – Puntland's elite Dervish forces have killed more than 35 ISIS militants, including several foreign fighters, during a major military operation carried out Tuesday in the rural area between Miraale and Balade in the Bari region, officials said.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 03:16 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201749/puntland_s_dervish_forces_kill_over_35_isis_fighters_in_bari_region_offensive.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Al-Shabaab seizes a Burundian helicopter after emergency landing in Middle Shabelle region
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201748/al_shabaab_seizes_a_burundian_helicopter_after_emergency_landing_in_middle_shabelle_region.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Al-Shabaab militants have displayed a helicopter that crash-landed near their territory in the Middle Shabelle region, following a technical malfunction during an evacuation mission by Burundian troops under the African Union Support and Stabilisation Mission in Somalia (AUSSOM).
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 02:29 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201748/al_shabaab_seizes_a_burundian_helicopter_after_emergency_landing_in_middle_shabelle_region.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    President Mohamud engages civil society ahead of National Consultation Forum
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201747/president_mohamud_engages_civil_society_ahead_of_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Somali President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud convened a high-level meeting with representatives from a broad cross-section of civil society at the Presidential Palace on Tuesday, marking a key step toward the National Consultation Forum scheduled for June 15, 2025.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 02:08 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201747/president_mohamud_engages_civil_society_ahead_of_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Elon Musk slams Trump’s signature budget bill as a ‘disgusting abomination’
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201746/elon_musk_slams_trump_s_signature_budget_bill_as_a_disgusting_abomination.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Billionaire Elon Musk has renewed his criticisms of United States President Donald Trump’s signature budget bill, calling it a “disgusting abomination” in a series of social media posts.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 02:04 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201746/elon_musk_slams_trump_s_signature_budget_bill_as_a_disgusting_abomination.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Human Rights Groups demand Kenya, Uganda to act over activists' torture in Tanzania
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201745/human_rights_groups_demand_kenya_uganda_to_act_over_activists_torture_in_tanzania.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Human rights groups are now asking Kenyan and Ugandan legislators to hold their governments accountable over the torture of their citizens in Tanzania.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Wed, 4 Jun 2025 01:56 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201745/human_rights_groups_demand_kenya_uganda_to_act_over_activists_torture_in_tanzania.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Man charged in Wayzata graduation shooting that injured Somali parent, teen
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201743/man_charged_in_wayzata_graduation_shooting_that_injured_somali_parent_teen.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    MINNEAPOLIS, Minnesota (HOL) — A 20-year-old man has been charged after allegedly shooting two people outside Wayzata High School’s graduation ceremony at the University of Minnesota’s Mariucci Arena, including a Somali-American father who was attending to celebrate his child’s milestone.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 15:40 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201743/man_charged_in_wayzata_graduation_shooting_that_injured_somali_parent_teen.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali military court jails Al-Shabaab bombmaker for life
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201742/somali_military_court_jails_al_shabaab_bombmaker_for_life.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somalia’s military court on Tuesday sentenced a key Al-Shabaab operative to life in prison for manufacturing vehicle-borne explosive devices as part of a broader crackdown on militant support networks.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 15:20 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201742/somali_military_court_jails_al_shabaab_bombmaker_for_life.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somaliland president wraps up Kenya visit, hails diplomatic progress
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201741/somaliland_president_wraps_up_kenya_visit_hails_diplomatic_progress.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    NAIROBI, Kenya (HOL) —Somaliland President Abdirahman Mohamed Abdullahi Irro has concluded a diplomatic visit to Kenya, calling the trip a success and reaffirming his commitment to strengthening Somaliland’s regional presence while upholding democratic principles.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 14:47 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201741/somaliland_president_wraps_up_kenya_visit_hails_diplomatic_progress.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Kenyan forces kill four Al-Shabaab militants in Garissa dawn raid
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201740/kenyan_forces_kill_four_al_shabaab_militants_in_garissa_dawn_raid.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    NAIROBI, Kenya (HOL) — Kenyan security forces killed four suspected Al-Shabaab militants during a dawn raid on Monday in Garissa County, northeastern Kenya, in what police described as a coordinated counterterrorism operation led by the elite Special Operations Group (SOG).
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 14:23 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201740/kenyan_forces_kill_four_al_shabaab_militants_in_garissa_dawn_raid.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali woman Marjama Osman killed in South London stabbing, police launch murder probe
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201739/somali_woman_marjama_osman_killed_in_south_london_stabbing_police_launch_murder_probe.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    LONDON, United Kingdom (HOL) — British police have launched a murder investigation after 26-year-old Marjama Osman, a Somali-British woman, was fatally stabbed in Croydon on Saturday morning—a killing that has reignited concern over rising knife violence affecting Somali youth in the UK.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 13:56 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201739/somali_woman_marjama_osman_killed_in_south_london_stabbing_police_launch_murder_probe.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia concludes arms control summit as Al-Shabaab IED threat grows
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201738/somalia_concludes_arms_control_summit_as_al_shabaab_ied_threat_grows.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somalia wrapped up a two-day national conference on arms and ammunition management in Mogadishu on Tuesday as government officials seek to curb the growing threat posed by improvised explosive devices (IEDs) used by Al-Shabaab militants.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 13:02 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201738/somalia_concludes_arms_control_summit_as_al_shabaab_ied_threat_grows.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    NISA kills senior Al-Shabaab operative in targeted operation in Lower Shabelle region
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201737/nisa_kills_senior_al_shabaab_operative_in_targeted_operation_in_lower_shabelle_region.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Somalia’s National Intelligence and Security Agency (NISA) has killed a senior Al-Shabaab operative during a targeted operation conducted Tuesday in the Lower Shabelle region, the federal government announced.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 11:47 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201737/nisa_kills_senior_al_shabaab_operative_in_targeted_operation_in_lower_shabelle_region.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Tailored learning helps displaced Somali girl thrive in math
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201736/tailored_learning_helps_displaced_somali_girl_thrive_in_math.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — In a modest classroom on the edge of Baidoa, 13-year-old Ifrah Mohamed stands confidently before the chalkboard, solving math problems with ease. Her transformation from a struggling student to a budding mentor is one example of how tailored instruction is reshaping education for displaced children across Somalia.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 07:50 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201736/tailored_learning_helps_displaced_somali_girl_thrive_in_math.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Turkey to send 500 troops to Somalia as part of expanded military, energy deal
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201735/turkey_to_send_500_troops_to_somalia_as_part_of_expanded_military_energy_deal.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Turkey will deploy 500 additional special forces to Somalia in a significant escalation of its military support for the Horn of Africa nation, as international peacekeeping efforts face budget constraints and rising threats from Al-Shabaab.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 07:37 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201735/turkey_to_send_500_troops_to_somalia_as_part_of_expanded_military_energy_deal.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia and Azerbaijan sign renewable energy deal as ties deepen across key sectors
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201734/somalia_and_azerbaijan_sign_renewable_energy_deal_as_ties_deepen_across_key_sectors.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somalia has signed a memorandum of understanding with Azerbaijan to enhance cooperation in the field of renewable energy, marking the latest step in Somalia's efforts to reform its energy sector.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 07:26 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201734/somalia_and_azerbaijan_sign_renewable_energy_deal_as_ties_deepen_across_key_sectors.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    AU troops evacuate Xawaadley after floods; reports suggest Al-Shabaab presence
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201733/au_troops_evacuate_xawaadley_after_floods_reports_suggest_al_shabaab_presence.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Burundian peacekeepers evacuated the Somali town of Xawaadley this week after heavy flooding overwhelmed their base, the African Union Support and Stabilisation Mission in Somalia (AUSSOM) said Tuesday. Local officials say Al-Shabaab may have re-entered the area following the withdrawal, though this remains unconfirmed.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 06:51 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201733/au_troops_evacuate_xawaadley_after_floods_reports_suggest_al_shabaab_presence.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali added to official Hajj sermon translations for first time
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201732/somali_added_to_official_hajj_sermon_translations_for_first_time.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — For the first time, Somali will be among the official languages used to translate key sermons during the Hajj pilgrimage, Somalia’s Minister of Endowments and Religious Affairs announced this week, marking a historic milestone for Somali-speaking Muslims participating in Islam’s most sacred ritual.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 06:36 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201732/somali_added_to_official_hajj_sermon_translations_for_first_time.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia partners with U.S., Interpol to share aviation security data
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201731/somalia_partners_with_u_s_interpol_to_share_aviation_security_data.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somalia has launched a real-time aviation data-sharing system in partnership with the United States and Interpol, aiming to bolster border security and improve screening at ports of entry as part of broader institutional reforms.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 06:17 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201731/somalia_partners_with_u_s_interpol_to_share_aviation_security_data.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    US airstrikes kill at least 10 ISIS militants in northeastern Somalia
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201730/us_airstrikes_kill_at_least_10_isis_militants_in_northeastern_somalia.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Bosaso (HOL) – At least ten ISIS militants were killed in new US airstrikes targeting militant hideouts in the mountainous areas between Balade and Miraale valleys, according to a statement released Tuesday by Puntland's anti-ISIS operation command.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 02:19 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201730/us_airstrikes_kill_at_least_10_isis_militants_in_northeastern_somalia.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali President holds phone talks with Qatari and Turkish leaders on development cooperation
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201729/somali_president_holds_phone_talks_with_qatari_and_turkish_leaders_on_security_and_development_cooperation.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – Somali President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud held a phone conversation with Qatari Amir Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al-Thani on Monday, focusing on strengthening bilateral relations.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 02:06 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201729/somali_president_holds_phone_talks_with_qatari_and_turkish_leaders_on_security_and_development_cooperation.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Raila Odinga reaffirms support for Somaliland recognition
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201728/raila_odinga_reaffirms_support_for_somaliland_recognition.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Nairobi (HOL) – Former Kenyan Prime Minister Raila Odinga has once again thrown his weight behind Somaliland’s quest for international recognition during a high-profile meeting with Somaliland President Abdirahman Mohamed Abdullahi Irro in Nairobi.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 01:52 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201728/raila_odinga_reaffirms_support_for_somaliland_recognition.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Canada to expedite nation building projects to counter Trump
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201727/canada_to_expedite_nation_building_projects_to_counter_trump.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney said his government will start pushing legislation that would fast-track ambitious national projects to boost Canada's economy, now faced with Donald Trump's tariffs.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 01:36 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201727/canada_to_expedite_nation_building_projects_to_counter_trump.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali-owned Hoyo will soon see its sambusas in Lunds and at the State Fair
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201726/somali_owned_hoyo_will_soon_see_its_sambusas_in_lunds_and_at_the_state_fair.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    The decade-old business is moving to a $1.6 million commercial kitchen at Midtown Global Market as it anticipates tripling in size.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 01:32 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201726/somali_owned_hoyo_will_soon_see_its_sambusas_in_lunds_and_at_the_state_fair.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Kenyan and Ugandan activists say they were sexually assaulted in Tanzania
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201725/kenyan_and_ugandan_activists_say_they_were_sexually_assaulted_in_tanzania.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    A Kenyan and a Ugandan human rights activist who were detained in Tanzania for several days last month said on Monday that Tanzanian security officers sexually assaulted them while in custody.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 3 Jun 2025 01:25 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201725/kenyan_and_ugandan_activists_say_they_were_sexually_assaulted_in_tanzania.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia launches national forum to counter illegal arms and IED threats
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201724/somalia_launches_national_forum_to_counter_illegal_arms_and_ied_threats.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somalia’s federal government launched a two-day national conference in Mogadishu on Monday to address the growing threat of illicit arms, unregulated ammunition, and improvised explosive devices (IEDs) used by insurgent groups.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 12:25 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201724/somalia_launches_national_forum_to_counter_illegal_arms_and_ied_threats.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Puntland salary crisis leaves civil servants unpaid for nearly a year
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201723/puntland_salary_crisis_leaves_civil_servants_unpaid_for_nearly_a_year.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Puntland government employees have gone unpaid for up to 10 months, with civil servants warning that prolonged salary delays are paralyzing state institutions and eroding public trust in the administration’s financial management.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 12:00 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201723/puntland_salary_crisis_leaves_civil_servants_unpaid_for_nearly_a_year.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somaliland issues coastal alert over strong winds and extreme heat
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201722/somaliland_issues_coastal_alert_over_strong_winds_and_extreme_heat.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Hargeisa (HOL) — Somaliland’s Coast Guard has warned of high winds and dangerous sea conditions expected to affect parts of the Gulf of Aden coastline, urging fishermen, tourists, and coastal residents to avoid unnecessary exposure as the region experiences soaring temperatures and rough waters.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 11:39 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201722/somaliland_issues_coastal_alert_over_strong_winds_and_extreme_heat.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Farmaajo backs Somalia’s national forum, urges inclusion of Puntland and Jubbaland
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201721/farmaajo_backs_somalia_s_national_forum_urges_inclusion_of_puntland_and_jubbaland.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Former Somali President Mohamed Abdullahi Farmaajo has endorsed the upcoming National Consultation Forum announced by President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud but urged full participation from federal member states and a reversal of what he described as damaging unilateral decisions.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 11:36 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201721/farmaajo_backs_somalia_s_national_forum_urges_inclusion_of_puntland_and_jubbaland.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali prime minister, Djibouti president hold security talks in Djibouti
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201720/somali_prime_minister_djibouti_president_hold_security_talks_in_djibouti.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Djibouti City, DJIBOUTI (HOL) — Somali Prime Minister Hamza Abdi Barre met with Djibouti’s President Ismail Omar Guelleh on Monday to strengthen bilateral cooperation and address growing regional security concerns in the Horn of Africa.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 11:19 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201720/somali_prime_minister_djibouti_president_hold_security_talks_in_djibouti.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Building a Nation’s Presence Abroad: The foundation of Somaliland’s foreign policy
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201719/building_a_nation_s_presence_abroad_the_foundation_of_somaliland_s_foreign_policy.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    A wise saying states, “Whoever desires to raise a high building must strengthen and perfect its foundation.” This principle, though originally intended to describe physical structures, applies powerfully to the realm of politics and diplomacy—particularly in the case of Somaliland. As a self-declared state striving for international recognition and broader global engagement, Somaliland’s foreign policy must be rooted in solid internal foundations. The success of its international outreach depends not just on external lobbying, but on the strength, unity, and integrity of its domestic systems.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 11:06 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201719/building_a_nation_s_presence_abroad_the_foundation_of_somaliland_s_foreign_policy.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somalia: President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud personifies toxic leadership
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201718/somalia_president_hassan_sheikh_mohamud_personifies_toxic_leadership.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    The people of Somalia endured painful historical misfortunes consisting of mockery of one-person-one-vote political elections that resulted in a military coup, a long period of dictatorship that was ousted with armed rebellion, an internecine civil war and complete disintegration of the Somali state replaced by foreign and clan dependency. Those misfortunes deeply affected the livelihood, perceptions, and conscience of the Somali people in multiple ways and undermined the foundations, values, perceptions, and social cohesion needed for rebuilding the Somali State.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 11:02 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/op4/2025/Jun/201718/somalia_president_hassan_sheikh_mohamud_personifies_toxic_leadership.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali opposition sets conditions for participation in upcoming national consultation forum
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201717/somali_opposition_sets_conditions_for_participation_in_upcoming_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) – The Somali Salvation Forum, a coalition made up primarily of opposition members, has laid out preconditions for participating in the national consultation conference announced by President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud, set to open on June 15, 2025, in Mogadishu.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 05:21 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201717/somali_opposition_sets_conditions_for_participation_in_upcoming_national_consultation_forum.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Somali government and AFRICOM conduct airstrikes targeting ISIS in Puntland
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201716/somali_government_and_africom_conduct_airstrikes_targeting_isis_in_puntland.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — Somali government, in coordination with the United States Africa Command (AFRICOM), has carried out two separate airstrikes targeting the Islamic State (ISIS) group in the Bari region of Puntland.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 03:03 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201716/somali_government_and_africom_conduct_airstrikes_targeting_isis_in_puntland.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Puntland bans Somaliland certificate exams in Badhan district, warns of strict action
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201715/puntland_bans_somaliland_certificate_exams_in_badhan_district_warns_of_strict_action.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Garowe (HOL) — The Puntland regional administration has officially banned the administration of the Somaliland certificate examination in the Badhan district of Sanaag region, a territory claimed by both Puntland and Somaliland.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 02:53 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201715/puntland_bans_somaliland_certificate_exams_in_badhan_district_warns_of_strict_action.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Wadajir Party slams selection process of Somalia's Human Rights Commission
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201714/wadajir_party_slams_selection_process_of_somalia_s_human_rights_commission.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    Mogadishu (HOL) — The Wadajir Party, led by Abdirahman Abdishakur Warsame, has rebuked the ongoing process for appointing members to Somalia's Independent Human Rights Commission, accusing the Presidency of interference and calling for an immediate suspension of the process.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 02:44 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201714/wadajir_party_slams_selection_process_of_somalia_s_human_rights_commission.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    UN-Habitat Assembly ends with adoption of strategic plan to tackle housing crisis
   </title>
   <link>
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201713/un_habitat_assembly_ends_with_adoption_of_strategic_plan_to_tackle_housing_crisis.aspx
   </link>
   <description>
    The resumed second session of the United Nations Habitat Assembly concluded late Friday in Nairobi, the Kenyan capital, with the adoption of a bold strategic plan aimed at tackling the global housing crisis.
   </description>
   <pubDate>
    Mon, 2 Jun 2025 02:31 EDT
   </pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">
    http://www.hiiraan.com/news4/2025/Jun/201713/un_habitat_assembly_ends_with_adoption_of_strategic_plan_to_tackle_housing_crisis.aspx
   </guid>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
